Guide to the University Center Activities and Events Records, 1981-2016 UA.09.12.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
University Center Activities and Events Records
1981-2016
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Office of Student Affairs. University Center Activities and Events
UA.09.12.0001
1.5 Linear Feet
The University Center Activities and Events (UCAE) creates opportunities for students to expand their knowledge outside of the classroom, and the UCAE Center for Leadership Development and Social Action (LDSA) provides students with opportunities to learn about and practice effective leadership. The collection includes programs, materials related to nomination and giving of awards, booklets, publications, and media.
Biographical / Historical
University Center Activities and Events (UCAE) creates opportunities for students to expand their knowledge outside of the classroom. The UCAE Center for Leadership Development and Social Action (LDSA) provides developmental learning experiences and resources to enable Duke students to practice effective leadership and inspire positive change within the Duke, local and global communities. LDSA uses the Duke University Leadership Framework and offers a variety of workshops, conferences, and retreats for students to learn about and practice leadership. LDSA also offers a numbmer of leadership and service awards for students.
Source: About UCAE Center for Leadership Development & Social Action website, https://studentaffairs.duke.edu/index.php/ucae/leadership/about-ucae-center-leadership-development-social-action, accessed 2017 August 03.
Access Restrictions
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
Use of audiotapes and videotapes from this collection requires the creation of reference copies. Reference copies for some materials may have been made, and if a reference copy exists, it is noted in this finding aid. To arrange for the creation of reference copies of other items, please contact University Archives staff. Although these recordings are now stored in a stable environment, their condition and playback quality is unknown.
Provenance
The University Center Activities and Events Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 2012 and 2016.
Scope and Contents
The collection includes materials related to events, workshops, seminars, and activities. Topics covered include the Student Leadership and Service Awards, including nominations, promotional materials; student leadership retreats; conference and leadership photographs; and other subjects. Materials include programs, posters, flyers, videocassettes, t-shirts, and electronic records.
Leadership -- Study and teaching; College students -- North Carolina -- Durham; Duke University. Office of Student Affairs. University Center Activities and Events
- Container List, 1999-2012, 1 box
  Scope and Contents note
  This material was created by the Leadership Development and Social Action Team within University Center Activities and Events.
  - Publications, 1999-2012 (Box 1)
  - Leadership Events, 2004-2008 (Box 1)
  - Programs, 1999-2012 (Box 1)
  - Student-Led Programs, 2006-2010 (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Student Leadership Conference Slides, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Student Leadership Conference Photos, 2008 (Box 1)
  - Campus Events Slides, undated (Box 1)
  - Beaufort Leadership Retreat, 2002 (VHS Master) (c.1, c.2) *User copy must be made for use. (Box 1)
  - Beaufort Leadership Presentation, 2002 (Mini-DV Master) *User copy must be made for use. (Box 1)
  - Electronic media: one CD w/ Student Affairs Leadership and Service Program, 2006, one CD with Awards ceremony, 2006 April 24 (all images), one CD with Office of Student Activities and Facilities images from student events 2007[?], one CD with Office of Student Activities and Facilities images from on-campus events such as Mo Rocca, Take Back the Night, 2005-2007[?], two 3.5" diskettes, undated regarding Griffith Award Info, GA Breakfast (Box 1)
- Center for Leadership Development and Social Action (LDSA), 1981-2016
  - Student Leadership and Service Awards Chronicle advertisements, 1981-2011 (Box 2)
  - Student Leadership and Service Awards guides and programs, 1983-2014 (Box 2)
  - Student Leadership and Service Awards nominations and name lists, 1988-2003 (Box 2)
  - Student Leadership and Service Awards promotional materials and invititations, 1993-2016 (Box 2)
  - Student Leadership and Service Awards award draft and nomination considerations, undated (Box 2)
  - Student leadership retreat booklets, 2006-2011 (Box 2)
  - Duke Partnership for Service report, 2011 (Box 2)
  - Leadership guides, 2012-2015 (Box 2)
  - LDSA handouts, 2013-2014 (Box 2)
  - Leadershape photographs, 2013-2014 (Box 2)
  - Leadershape t-shirts, 2013-2014 (Box 3)
  - Duke Authenticity Project materials, 2014 (Box 2)
  - Duke Authenticity Project t-shirt, 2014 (Box 3)
  - Penny Pilgrim George Women's Leadership Initiative (PPGWLI) materials, 2016 (Box 2)
  - Leadership retreat photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - 3 Words video for Leadership Banquet, 2014 (Box 2, Optical-disc UA09120001-OP-0002)